Theodore Idoko

Bochum, Germany

idokotheodore@gmail.com +4917680155851

https://www.linkedin.com/in/theodore-idoko-031039189ä

Summary

I am a Frontend developer who also have reasonable experience of backend. MERN Stack precisely. Coming from the field of User experience design before moving into Web development, I aim at developing and creating human centered design solutions with empathy. JavaScript, React, Bootstrap, CSS/HTML, jQuery, Sass, Node, Nest*, Express, Node Package Manager, API CRUD operation, Database, MongoDb and Mongoose, Deployment, Git and GitHub, Adobe XD, Figma etc. I also have good knowledge of Python and currently enthusiastic to learn Django. I am a critical thinker, a life-long learner and surprisingly fast at picking up new concepts. I am also fluent in German and English language

Experience

Front End Developer

Stutern

June 2020 – Sep 2020 (4 months)

Stutern is a Software Engineering Bootcamp that helps student start a career in the software industry. I worked on rebuilding a new website for the company. I specifically worked as a Front-End Developer

Information Technology Intern

Cico Serve

June 2019 - August 2019

A financial Startup that was beginning at the time. Did my internship there after doing a UIUX Bootcamp. I helped design some of their products with Figma.

Education

Ruhr University Bochum

Computer Science

Oct 2021 to present

Studienkolleg des Ökumenischen Studienwerks e.V

Oct 2020 - April 2021

DSH ZEUGNIS

Stutern

Student Graduate Accelerator, Software Engineering Training

Oct 2019 - June 2020

Activities and societies: Worked on projects with product designers and developers. Activities and societies: Worked on projects with product designers and developers.

Full-stack software development learnt using JavaScript and its framework like React, NodeJS.

Lagos State Employability Support Project

March 2019 – May 2019

Vocational Training exercise implemented by Lagos State and United Nations Development program (UNDP). Certified in UI/UX.

Nnamdi Azikiwe University

Bachelor of Arts-BA Philosophy

Oct 2011 - Jul 2015

Licenses & Certifications

MTA: Software Development Fundamentals- Certified 2022